<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Navelgazing on Tiny Human House</title>
    <link>/categories/navelgazing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Navelgazing on Tiny Human House</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:27:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/navelgazing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The last time</title>
      <link>/posts/the-last-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-last-time/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a comic I like recently and it made me burst into tears. How Baby Comic talked about an ask reddit thread where people talked about the saddest sentence they could think of, and the author quoted:
 &#34;one day, your parents put you down and never picked you back up again.&#34; We are in that zone now, things are shifting away slowly to a different stage, he&amp;rsquo;s ready to be more independent, and I am working on let go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sick Mama, Sick Baby</title>
      <link>/posts/sick-mama-sick-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 17:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sick-mama-sick-baby/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re feeling a lot better now, but we&amp;rsquo;ve been sick for about a week - before us it was my partner that was sick, then the rest of us caught it eventually. My goal was to take it as easy as possible - and to encourage my son to do the same. The weather was pretty mediocre as well, so it lent it self well to staying indoors for the most part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The way people treat children</title>
      <link>/posts/the-way-people-treat-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 18:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-way-people-treat-children/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not alone in how I see children, there are people that inspire me to be better and more thoughtful and more patient - folks like Robin Enzig of Visible Child and Teacher Tom. Having expectations are developmentally appropriate and fair make things a lot easier. Boundaries are created and kept and gently supported. Feelings are allowed. Children are supported and set up for success instead of pushed towards one thing or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year of Mama</title>
      <link>/posts/one-year-of-mama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 02:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/one-year-of-mama/</guid>
      <description>My baby is one year old.
While obviously, this is a significant milestone for him - I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find a balance between telling my story, and not telling his. The often forgotten part of birthday&amp;rsquo;s are parents - and I know I never gave my parents much thought when I was growing up and it was my birthday. It was just me. Now I feel like I should have at least gotten my mom a card&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>