<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tiny Human House</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tiny Human House</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 15:37:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Riot&#39;s 2019 Read Harder Challenge</title>
      <link>/posts/book-riots-2019-read-harder-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 15:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/book-riots-2019-read-harder-challenge/</guid>
      <description>I did BookRiot&amp;rsquo;s 2018 Read Harder Challenge, and it got me out of my usual genres and connected me with books I really loved that weren&amp;rsquo;t ones I would have picked up.
After our Tinyhuman was born, I had a really challenging time focusing on books for the first year or two, but in 2018, I managed to read over 40 books, at least in part as a result of the ReadHarderChallenge, but also just because my focus came back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field-trips with Friends</title>
      <link>/posts/field-trips-with-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 14:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/field-trips-with-friends/</guid>
      <description>Today my adventure began bright and early. I went downtown (by myself) to take part in the Sunrise Ceremony at the IRSS Legacy Celebration at Nathan Phillips Square. I was late arriving and stood back and watched, I think I could have joined in. I probably should have, but felt uncomfortable and disrespectful about being late for it. (I have this thing with time.)
But it felt meaningful and with intention, as a fairly large group gathered to acknowledge the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Forest School Day</title>
      <link>/posts/a-forest-school-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 16:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-forest-school-day/</guid>
      <description>This morning after my partner left for work, we quickly got ready to get outside and go to the forest nearby. We&amp;rsquo;re lucky to hour our little forest, and I feel grateful to say things like &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s visit our trees&amp;rdquo; on a regular basis. There was so much to learn and so much to do. We walked hand in hand for most of the trip to the park, but once we got past the traffic gates I let him go and he asked if he could run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mom Tiger is Sick - Rest is Best.</title>
      <link>/posts/mom-tiger-is-sick-rest-is-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 01:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mom-tiger-is-sick-rest-is-best/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been sick for a few days and I feel bummed out about it - there is so much I&amp;rsquo;d like to do, and so much I&amp;rsquo;d rather be doing, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to rest as much as possible.
The sad thing is that I&amp;rsquo;m conscious of how much I&amp;rsquo;d love to be cleaning or doing laundry or all the things I normally and eagerly set aside - in favour of this deeply exhausted feeling in my muscles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last time</title>
      <link>/posts/the-last-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-last-time/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a comic I like recently and it made me burst into tears. How Baby Comic talked about an ask reddit thread where people talked about the saddest sentence they could think of, and the author quoted:
 &#34;one day, your parents put you down and never picked you back up again.&#34; We are in that zone now, things are shifting away slowly to a different stage, he&amp;rsquo;s ready to be more independent, and I am working on let go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering Tiny Humans - Step One</title>
      <link>/posts/fostering-tiny-humans-step-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 16:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/fostering-tiny-humans-step-one/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I filled out the form on the Children&amp;rsquo;s Aid Society website indicating an interest to become a foster home. They sent back a message checking in with me, asking whether I was aware of the different religious and cultural based foster agencies in the city, and confirmed whether we wanted to proceed with them (we do).
So now we wait. Our next step is arranging a mutually amicable phone conversation - which I&amp;rsquo;m already nervous about, but also ready to do anytime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sick Mama, Sick Baby</title>
      <link>/posts/sick-mama-sick-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 17:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sick-mama-sick-baby/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re feeling a lot better now, but we&amp;rsquo;ve been sick for about a week - before us it was my partner that was sick, then the rest of us caught it eventually. My goal was to take it as easy as possible - and to encourage my son to do the same. The weather was pretty mediocre as well, so it lent it self well to staying indoors for the most part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The way people treat children</title>
      <link>/posts/the-way-people-treat-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 18:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-way-people-treat-children/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not alone in how I see children, there are people that inspire me to be better and more thoughtful and more patient - folks like Robin Enzig of Visible Child and Teacher Tom. Having expectations are developmentally appropriate and fair make things a lot easier. Boundaries are created and kept and gently supported. Feelings are allowed. Children are supported and set up for success instead of pushed towards one thing or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new year, same great us</title>
      <link>/posts/new-year-same-great-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 03:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-year-same-great-us/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday morning we bundled up and got ready for the ymca. It&amp;rsquo;s become a regular thing, this guaranteed Tuesday morning visit to the Y - why? Because we have a regular cleaner now, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get out of the house and get out of their way. I&amp;rsquo;d rather spend time with the TinyHuman than spend anymore time organizing, cleaning, scrubbing, over and over and over again, Instead, we leave, and come back to a nicely organized, clean house - then it&amp;rsquo;s nap time, and I get to take care of dinner things or read books or watch movies or some combination of those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We went outside and other things</title>
      <link>/posts/we-went-outside-and-other-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 04:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/we-went-outside-and-other-things/</guid>
      <description>The Tinyhuman had a swimming lesson this morning - he went with his dad, and I slept in until the glorious time of 9am. I&amp;rsquo;m getting pretty into these Saturday mornings where I sleep in, and then do some housework while they go play in the pool. In my head, I thought maybe I would start going to the gym, but I end up doing things I have a hard time doing while the kid is at home instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learned - Owls, Trucks, Nature programming, more owls</title>
      <link>/posts/what-we-learned-owls-trucks-nature-programming-more-owls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-we-learned-owls-trucks-nature-programming-more-owls/</guid>
      <description>Every Wednesday we watch the garbage or recycling truck from the front window - conveniently we have been reading Digger, Dozer, Dumper, an amazingly fun and wonderful board book with a couple pages focused on a garbage truck. When we hear the familiar rumble of the waste disposal truck - my son looked at me, and I looked at him, and I suggested we go look out the window at what they were doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Vegan Menu Planning #3 -</title>
      <link>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 01:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-3/</guid>
      <description>I started my planning process earlier this time around, so there is no scramble to make a plan and also it gave a little time to go along and comment on the week as things happened.
How did we do with last week&amp;rsquo;s plan? I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth analyzing how last weeks meal plan worked out as I create this new one. I probably had too many ambitious dishes on the roster for last week, especially when we also had too much stuff on the go with non-food life related things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Vegan Menu Planning #2</title>
      <link>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-2/</guid>
      <description>I should start thinking about the weeks ahead during the week before, but we get to Sunday and I remember it&amp;rsquo;s time to put our grocery order in. Grocery order? Well - our local grocer has an online option so someone else picks our groceries for us and we load it into our car.
We just pick them up. This still usually involves a quick run through for items we might have forgotten or to pick up some beer or cider, but generally, it keeps our time there as short as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Human House, Tiny Houses, She Sheds</title>
      <link>/posts/tiny-human-house-tiny-houses-she-sheds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 22:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tiny-human-house-tiny-houses-she-sheds/</guid>
      <description>Somehow I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a bit obsessed with the idea of a She Sheds. Or just, having a tiny shed in the garden to escape and read or craft or write in. It&amp;rsquo;s part of a large effort to simplify things in the house, and make the house as safe as possible for our little one, but also, just symbolic of my need to have something that is mine. All mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year of Mama</title>
      <link>/posts/one-year-of-mama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 02:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/one-year-of-mama/</guid>
      <description>My baby is one year old.
While obviously, this is a significant milestone for him - I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find a balance between telling my story, and not telling his. The often forgotten part of birthday&amp;rsquo;s are parents - and I know I never gave my parents much thought when I was growing up and it was my birthday. It was just me. Now I feel like I should have at least gotten my mom a card&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A week of dinners - sunday meal planning</title>
      <link>/posts/a-week-of-dinners-sunday-meal-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 02:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-week-of-dinners-sunday-meal-planning/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on getting more organized in terms of making dinner. If I work that day, or we have a bunch of playdates, we are more likely to order in or get take out. Sometimes my partner cooks, but I usually have to come up with the idea or find a recipe that works with what we have in the house. Sometimes that seems like more effort than just opening the fridge, and making something up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The day our son was born.</title>
      <link>/posts/the-day-our-son-was-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 23:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-day-our-son-was-born/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to start where our tiny human house began. The day our son was born. I wrote this originally on Apr 18, 2016 @ 12:24, but have edited it a tiny bit, and added a few more details along the way.
Throughout my pregnancy, I had been planning for a home birth. Home is where I feel safe and comfortable, so I thought it would be a great place to have our baby – and I was low risk and had a very easy pregnancy, so I was an ideal candidate for a home birth too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>