<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mealplanning on Tiny Human House</title>
    <link>/categories/mealplanning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mealplanning on Tiny Human House</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 01:08:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/mealplanning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Vegan Menu Planning #3 -</title>
      <link>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 01:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-3/</guid>
      <description>I started my planning process earlier this time around, so there is no scramble to make a plan and also it gave a little time to go along and comment on the week as things happened.
How did we do with last week&amp;rsquo;s plan? I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth analyzing how last weeks meal plan worked out as I create this new one. I probably had too many ambitious dishes on the roster for last week, especially when we also had too much stuff on the go with non-food life related things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Vegan Menu Planning #2</title>
      <link>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 10:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weekly-vegan-menu-planning-2/</guid>
      <description>I should start thinking about the weeks ahead during the week before, but we get to Sunday and I remember it&amp;rsquo;s time to put our grocery order in. Grocery order? Well - our local grocer has an online option so someone else picks our groceries for us and we load it into our car.
We just pick them up. This still usually involves a quick run through for items we might have forgotten or to pick up some beer or cider, but generally, it keeps our time there as short as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A week of dinners - sunday meal planning</title>
      <link>/posts/a-week-of-dinners-sunday-meal-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 02:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-week-of-dinners-sunday-meal-planning/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on getting more organized in terms of making dinner. If I work that day, or we have a bunch of playdates, we are more likely to order in or get take out. Sometimes my partner cooks, but I usually have to come up with the idea or find a recipe that works with what we have in the house. Sometimes that seems like more effort than just opening the fridge, and making something up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>